<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<entries>

    <entry>
        <name>Historical Grounds Tour</name>
        <location>Alnwick Castle</location>
        <details>Hear thrilling and harrowing stories from the long and eventful history of Alnwick Castle, as you walk the grounds with one of our knowledgeable guides. Alnwick Castle has been at the forefront of history for centuries. From attacks by Scottish kings to resident knights like Harry Hotspur, through to restorations in the Georgian and Victorian eras, there is always more to discover.</details>
		<link>https://www.visitnorthumberland.com/family-event/historical-grounds-tour-</link>
        <date>21/06/2020 - 23/09/2020</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Romeo &amp; Juliet - Outdoor Shakepspeare performance</name>
        <location>Alnwick Castle</location>
        <details>Join us in the grounds of Hulne Abbey for an unforgettable night as The Three Inch Fools perform Romeo and Juliet in this outdoor theatre performance. This romantic epic will be getting the full Three Inch Fools treatment: live music-making, deft physically and vibrant story-telling. Expect fast-paced drama, plenty of musical instruments and many a quick costume change along the way! Gates open from 6pm. Performance starts at 7pm. Tickets to be released on 27th March For more information, please visit our website.</details>
		<link>https://www.visitnorthumberland.com/shows-displays/romeo-juliet-outdoor-shakespeare-performance</link>
        <date>4/07/2020 6pm</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <name>Fighting Knights</name>
        <location>Alnwick Castle</location>
        <details>Hear Alnwick Castle’s wall ring once again with the sounds of clashing steel in this gripping performance of epic proportions. Witness the drama, pageantry and passion as two armoured knights invoke the ancient right of Trial by Combat. Commonly applied by the medieval judiciary system, Trial by Combat was a method which settled accusations in the absence of witnesses or used to resolve legal disputes- in which the victor would be proclaimed to be right. Employing years of historical combat expertise, as well as fighting styles extracted directly from original 15th Century manuscripts, this Trial by Combat performance is breathtakingly enjoyable and an accurate portrayal of chivalry in a medieval context.
Cheer on either Sir Lewis or Sir Jay as these two highly skilled knights battle one another in single combat. These duelling gentlemen fight using a range of deadly weapons produced from their own armoury. This terrific and fun filled family entertainment of fighting knights is free with admission to Alnwick Castle! Please check the ‘What’s On’ board upon arrival for timings and locations, as these can vary throughout the season.
</details>
		<link>https://www.visitnorthumberland.com/family-event/fighting-knights-</link>
        <date>26/05/2020 - 29/05/2020</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Alpaca Minitreks</name>
        <location>Bamburgh Castle</location>
        <details>A first for Bamburgh Castle as these super-cute camelids come to meet our visitors. Hang out with these friendly alpacas for a selfie and a cuddle, or go on a mini-alpaca trek for a unique experience around the castle’s grounds. Charges apply for mini alpaca treks.</details>
		<link> https://www.beirhope.co.uk/</link>
        <date>14/04/2020 11am</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <name>Medieval Archery </name>
        <location>Bamburgh Castle</location>
        <details>Try your hand at archery with bow and arrow sessions with everyone’s favourite medieval archer – Rusty Bodkins. it’s not quite as easy as you think! </details>
		<link>https://www.bamburghcastle.com/whats-on/</link>
        <date>08/05/2020 - 09/05/2020</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Anglo Saxon Week</name>
        <location>Bamburgh Castle</location>
        <details>Celebrating Bamburgh Castle’s incredible past as an Anglo-Saxon Royal capital and citadel.
Recreating Anglo-Saxon period through to the 11th Century. Acle offer demonstrations of living history and combat from their own authentic encampment.
At the heart of the living history encampment is the kitchen where butter, ale, cheese and huge quantities of other food to keep the warriors happy is produced. You will love to see food being cooked in the camp kitchen and the smell of wood smoke adds to the atmosphere and sets the scene.

</details>
		<link>https://www.bamburghcastle.com/whats-on/</link>
        <date>23/05/2020 – 25/05/2020</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Warkworth Show</name>
        <location>Warkworth Castle</location>
        <details>Held annually in mid-August since 1859 in the grounds of Warkworth Castle, Warkworth Show offers visitors the unique opportunity to explore one of Northumberland's iconic castles as well as experiencing an integral part of village life in this historic community</details>
		<link>http://warkworthshow.co.uk/</link>
        <date>22/08/2020</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Knight’s Tournament</name>
        <location>Warkworth Castle</location>
        <details>Go back in time and get closer to the action as rival knights compete in the ultimate test of strength and skill at the Warkworth Castle Knights’ Tournament this May. Arrows will fly, swords will clash and the winner will be decided in the Grand Melee finale. Archery, single combat, learn more about the process of a knight getting ready for battle. Live medieval music. Meet our resident medieval jester and other medieval people. Get your tickets now and book your place at one of history’s most spectacular sporting contests.</details>
		<link>https://www.english-heritage.org.uk/visit/whats-on/warkworth-castle-knights-tournament-23-25-may-2020/</link>
        <date>23/05/2020 - 25/05/2020 11am</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Vintage Rally</name>
        <location>Paxton House</location>
        <details>
Paxton House Vintage Rally was started back in 2000 and this year is its 20th year! It was decided to start a vintage rally at Paxton House with the money raised going to charity, over the years the rally has grown and is now part of the vintage scene in the Scottish Borders with exhibitors coming from county Durham, Dumfries, Midloithian, Northumberland and the Borders.
</details>
		<link>https://paxtonhouse.co.uk/event/vintage-rally-3/</link>
        <date>21/06/2020 10am</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Outdoor Theatre – A Midsummer Night’s Dream</name>
        <location>Paxton House</location>
        <details>In Illyria’s 25th anniversary season this inimitable company reprises the show they performed in their very first year. Five couples – three human, one fairy, and one mythical – find their relationships sorely tested, intimately probed and indecently exposed when a troupe of amateur theatricals bumble into the forest to rehearse a play.  Add to this bawdy mix a heady brew of confusion, magic and mischief, and you have the most perfectly frothy comedy for a moonlit summer evening.

Please bring your own camping chairs, picnic blankets and warm clothing for the evening. There will be limited chairs and picnic benches available for those who do not have their own camping chairs.
Paxton House tearoom will be open and serving hot food, traybakes and refreshments before and during the performance.
</details>
		<link>https://paxtonhouse.co.uk/event/outdoor-theatre-a-midsummer-nights-dream/</link>
        <date>11/07/2020 8pm</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Easter Saturday Roman Fayre</name>
        <location>Arbeia Roman Fort</location>
        <details>Browse the Roman market, see gladiators doing battle, have-a-go at archery or get involved in the hands-on craft activities all from historical tents.</details>
		<link>https://arbeiaromanfort.org.uk/whats-on/easter-saturday-roman-fayre</link>
        <date>11/04/2020 11am</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Militaria Exhibition</name>
        <location>Vindolanda Fort</location>
        <details>A temporary exhibition at the Roman Army Museum showing an assembly of militiary artefacts never seen in pulbic which are on private loan to the Vindolanda Trust.

Over 40 objects are being loaned to the museum from a private collector and highlights include a complete legionary helmet found at a site in Wiesbaden-Erbenheim (Germany) in 1970/71 and a military diploma bestowing Roman Citizenship to Longinus Festius who served as a member of a unit of Syrian archers and who were later stationed at Magna, the fort next to the Roman Army Museum. This collection of artefacts will also highlight a range of fascinating fibula or brooches illustrating the Roman soldiers flare for the decorative.
</details>
		<link>https://www.vindolanda.com/Event/militaria-exhibition</link>
        <date>01/04/2020 - 31/10/2020 </date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
	<entry>
        <name>Archaeology Half Term</name>
        <location>Chesters Roman Fort</location>
        <details>This half term, join in the adventurous quest of our two Victorian time travellers who helped discover Chesters' Roman remains and its ancient artefacts. Find out about the tools used to excavate discoveries, take part in activities to guess what the fragments from the past were used for and visit our museum to see Roman objects and original archaeology on display.</details>
		<link>https://www.english-heritage.org.uk/visit/whats-on/chesters-roman-fort-archaeology-half-term-23-31-may-2020/</link>
        <date>23/05/2020 - 31/05/2020 11am</date>
        <gallery>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
            <image>
                <file_name></file_name>
                <attribution></attribution>
            </image>
        </gallery>
    </entry>
</entries>